Elsie Clews Parsons Papers 1835-1944 Mss.Ms.Coll.29
American Philosophical Society
- Elsie Clews Parsons Papers II, 1898-1937
  - Series III. Lectures and Manuscripts, 1898-1947
    - Manuscripts (Box Papers-II Series-III: 1)
      - Manuscripts - Alexander M. Stephen's Hopi Journal, [ca. 1936] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 6)
        - Folder #1a (Box Papers-II Series-III: 6)
          original proofs photocopy of Folder #1a
        - Folder #1b (Box Papers-II Series-III: 6)
        - Folders #2-8 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 6)
      - Manuscripts - Alexander M. Stephen's Hopi Journal, [ca. 1936] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 7)
        - Folder #9 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 7)
      - Manuscripts - Alexander M. Stephen's Hopi Journal - Correspondence, 1903; 1926-1936 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 7)
        - Boas, Franz (Box Papers-II Series-III: 7)
        - Bunzel, Ruth L. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 7)
        - Dellenbaugh, Frederick S. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 7)
        - Whorf, Benjamin L. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 7)
          -See also Ser. VIII, Stephen, Alexander M.
      - Manuscripts - "Suffrage and Feminism", 2 Folders (Box Papers-II Series-III: 7)
      - Manuscripts - "A Suggestion for Ethnology in the Philippines", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 7)
      - Manuscripts - [Supernaturalism], n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 7)
      - Manuscripts - "Survivals of Indian Culture among Zapoteca-Speaking Mexicans", [ca. 1932] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 7)
      - Manuscripts - "Taos Pueblo", 1936 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 7)
      - Manuscripts - "Time-Keeping", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 7)
      - Manuscripts - "Tar Baby", [1929] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 7)
      - Manuscripts - "The Tourist Eliminated", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 7)
      - Manuscripts - "Towards Keeping the Peace: Essays of a Pacifist", [ca. 1917]; 7 Folders (Box Papers-II Series-III: 7)
      - Manuscripts - "Towards Keeping the Peace: Essays of a Pacifist" - Clippings, 1914-17; 6 Folders (Box Papers-II Series-III: 7)
      - Manuscripts - "Towards Keeping the Peace: Essays of a Pacifist" - Notes, [1914-17] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 8)
      - Manuscripts - "Toy Soldier" - Correspondence, 1915 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 8)
      - Manuscripts - "Two Hindu Genealogies", [ca. 1925]; 3 Folders (Box Papers-II Series-III: 8)
        -For related information, see also Ser.IV, Hindu (Bose) - Notebooks #1-3, 1923; and Hindu - Notes
      - Manuscripts - "Two Hindu Genealogies" [Revised], [ca. 1925]; 3 Folders (Box Papers-II Series-III: 8)
      - Manuscripts - "Two Methods in Ethnological Hypothesis", 1917 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 8)
      - Manuscripts - "Vitance", n.d.; 2 Folders (Box Papers-II Series-III: 8)
      - Manuscripts - [War Essays], n.d.; 8 Folders (Box Papers-II Series-III: 8)
      - Manuscripts - "War Verses", [1934?] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 8)
      - Manuscripts - "The Will to Power among Sociologists", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 8)
      - Manuscripts - "Women and War" (Box Papers-II Series-III: 8)
      - Manuscripts - "Zapoteca Serpents", 1930 (Box Papers-II Series-III: 8)
      - Manuscripts - "Zuni Tales", [ca. 1930?] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 8)
        (end of manuscripts)
      - Miscellaneous Writings, [1885?] (Box Papers-II Series-III: 8)
      - Poems, n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-III: 8)
  - Series IV. Research Notes, 1880-1935?
    contains primarily notes on Indians of the Southwest, especially the Hopi and the Zuni, and Mexico. The Mexican material includes two handwritten manuscripts of "La Conquista," which relates the historical events between Montezuma and Cortez. The undated "Conquista" manuscript contains elaborate pen-and-ink drawings. There is also a large section of notes on Arabic and Sudanese folklore, as well as that of Nova Scotia, the Cape Verde Islands, and several other island communities. In addition, there is a smaller section of notes on the folklore of African-American communities. This series also includes the stenographer's notebooks kept by Parsons' secretary, Anne Nagle, from the years 1929-1935?. All of Nagle's notebooks are taken in Gregg shorthand, and contain correspondence, notes and tales. Notebooks and notes are arranged alphabetically by subject, and then chronologically within each subject. Unidentified notes appear in this series under "Miscellaneous." The bulk dates for the notebooks are from 1915 to 1932.
    - Acoma - Notebook, 1915-16 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 1)
      -See Ser.IV, Zuni - Notebook, 1915-16
    - Acoma - Notebook, 1917 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 1)
    - [African Proverbs] collected by Monroe N. Work, 1919 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 1)
      some in French
      - Work, Monroe N. (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 1)
    - Alaskan Eskimos - Notes, 1920 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 1)
    - American Ethnology SW - Notebook, 1910-12; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 1)
      - Goddard, P.E. (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 1)
      - Hilles, Charles D. (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 1)
      - Holmes, W.H. (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 1)
      - Parsons, Herbert, [1912] (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 1)
      - U.S. Dept. of the Interior (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 1)
    - [American Folklore] - Notes, 1895-1903; 1919; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 1)
      incl. tales, riddles
      -See also Ser.III, Mss. - [Negro Folklore]
      -See also Ser.IV, [Negro Folklore] - Notes
    - American Folklore - Notes, 1920; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 1)
      tales
    - Azores - Notes (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 1)
      riddles and tales
      -See Ser.IV, Cape Verde Islands/Azores - Notes
      -See Ser.IV, [Negro Folklore] - Notes
    - Bahamas/Haiti - Notebook, 1912 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 1)
    - Barbados - Notebook, 1924 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 1)
    - Bermuda, 1923; 2 Notebooks (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 1)
    - Black American Folklore (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 1)
      -See Ser.IV, [American Folklore] - Notes, 1895-1903; 1919; n.d.
    - Boas Address to American Folklore Society - Notes, 1900 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 1)
    - Cape Verde Islands/Azores - Notes (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 1)
      in Portuguese
    - Chorti - Notes taken by Charles Wisdom, [ca. 1935?] (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 1)
      " Mem. from the Chorti of Eastern Guatemala (ms.) - Charles Wisdom"
    - Cora/Huichol - Notes, [1933] (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 1)
    - Domingo Kinship Terms - Notes, n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 1)
    - Duke, James B.[?] - Notes, n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 1)
    - Egypt/Khartoum (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 2)
      -For related materials, see also: Ser.IV, Egyptian, Sudanese and Arabian Tales - Notes, 1926; Khartoum - Notebook by George Boutros, 1926; Sudanese Tales - Notes, 1926
      - Notebook #1, 1926 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 2)
        Egypt 1-27
      - Notebook #2, [1926] (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 2)
        Egypt 28-45, list of contents
      - Notebook #3, 1926 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 2)
        Egypt, Khartoum 1-21, list of contents
      - Notebook #4, [1926] (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 2)
        Khartoum
      - Notebook #5, [1926] (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 2)
      - Notebook #6, 1926 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 2)
        Khartoum 62-77, some in Arabic, list of contents
      - Notebook #7, [1926] (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 2)
        Khartoum 78-92
      - Notebook #8, [1926] (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 2)
        Khartoum 93-110
      - Notebook #9, [1926] (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 2)
        Khartoum, Egypt 47-62
      - Notebook #10, [1926] (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 2)
        Egypt 63-83
      - Notebook #11, [1926] (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 2)
        Egypt 84, lists of contents & informants
    - [Egyptian, Sudanese and Arabian Folk Tales] - Notes, 1926 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 2)
      some in Arabic
      - Pronger, Dorothy (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 2)
        -For related materials, see also: Ser.IV, Egypt/Khartoum - Notebooks; Khartoum - Notebook by George Boutros, 1926
    - Guatemala - Notes, n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 2)
      in Spanish, riddles
    - Haiti - Notebook, 1912 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 2)
      -See Ser.IV, Bahamas/Haiti - Notebook, 1912
    - Hano - Notebook, [1920] (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 2)
      -See also Ser.IV, Zuni - Notes by Alfred L. Kroeber, Folders #1-5, [ca. 1919?]
    - Havasupai Language - Notebook taken by Frank Hamilton Cushing, 1881 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 2)
    - Hindu (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 2)
      -For related materials, see also: Ser.III, Mss. - Folklore from the Dacca District, Bengal; A Romantic in Bengal and in New York; Two Hindu Genealogies
    - Hindu (Bose), 1923; 3 Notebooks (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 2)
      Informant: Somesh Chandra Bose
    - Hindu - Notes, [1923] (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 2)
      - Columbia University. Library (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 2)
    - Hopi (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 2)
      -For related materials, see also: Ser.IV, [Indian Languages] - Notebook; Zuni - Notes by Alfred L. Kroeber, Folders #1-5, [ca. 1919?]
    - Hopi, Jun. 1920 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 2)
      - Notebook #1, Jun. 1920 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 2)
      - Notebook #2, 10 Jun. (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 2)
      - Notebook #3, 9 Jun. (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 2)
      - Notebook #4, 10 Jun. (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 2)
      - Notebook #5, 11 Jun. (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 2)
      - Notebook #6, [Jun.] (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 2)
    - Hopi, Nov.-Dec. 1920 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 3)
      8 notebooks
      - Notebook #1, 20 Nov. (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 3)
      - Notebook #2, 20 Nov. (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 3)
      - Notebook #3, 22 Nov. (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 3)
      - Notebook #4, 24 Nov. (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 3)
      - Notebook #5, 24 Nov. (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 3)
      - Notebook #6[a], 28 Nov. (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 3)
      - Notebook #6[b], 30 Nov. (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 3)
      - Notebook #7, 3 Dec. (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 3)
    - [Hopi] - Notebook, [1922?] (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 3)
      reading notes
    - Hopi - Notes, 1929; 1932; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 3)
      - Forde, C. Daryll (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 3)
      - Lowie, Robert H. (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 3)
      - White, Leslie A. (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 3)
    - Hopi-Tewa, 1924; 2 Notebooks (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 4)
    - Huichol - Notes, [1933] (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 4)
      -See Ser.IV, Cora/Huichol - Notes
    - [Indian Languages] - Notebook, [1880?] (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 4)
      languages collected include: Hopi, Tewa
    - [Indians of North America] (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 4)
      map
    - Isleta (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 4)
      - Notebook #1, 1920 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 4)
        -See Ser.IV, San Felipe - Notebook, 1920
      - Notebook #2, 1920 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 4)
        contains San[to] Domingo material
    - Isleta at Zuni - Notebook, 1926 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 4)
      -See Ser.IV, Laguna - Notebook, 1926
    - Jemez, N.M. (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 4)
      -For additional materials, see also Ser.IV, Zuni - Notes by Alfred L. Kroeber, Folders #1-5, [ca.1919?]
    - Jemez, N.M., 1921; 3 Notebooks (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 4)
    - Jemez, N.M. - Notebook, 1922 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 4)
    - Kaiowa, 1927 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 4)
      - Notebooks #1-2 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 4)
      - Notebook #3 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 5)
    - Khartoum - Notebooks by ECP, 1926 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 5)
      -See Ser.IV, Egypt/Khartoum - Notebooks #1-11, 1926
    - Khartoum - Notebook by George Boutros Boutros, George, 1926 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 5)
    - Laguna (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 5)
    - Laguna - Notebook, 1917 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 5)
    - Laguna, 1918; 2 Notebooks (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 5)
    - Laguna - Notes, Oct. 1918 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 5)
    - Laguna - Notebook, 1919 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 5)
    - Laguna - Notes, 1919; 3 Folders (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 5)
    - Laguna - Notebook, Jun. 1920 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 5)
      ethnobotany
      -See Ser.IV, Hopi-Notebook #3, 9 Jun. 1920
    - Laguna, 1920; 2 Notebooks (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 5)
    - Laguna - Notebook, 1926 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 6)
      - Isleta at Zuni, 1926 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 6)
      - Pima - Notebook, 1926 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 6)
    - [Laguna - Border of Church Floor in?], n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 6)
      -For related materials, see Ser.IV, Laguna - Notebooks
    - Laguna Songs - Notes (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 6)
      -See Ser.IV, Zuni and Laguna Songs - Notes
    - Living Arrangements - Inventory and Summary (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 6)
    - Martha's Vineyard - Notes, 1919 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 6)
      Lucinia Jeffers, informant
    - Mexico - Notes, 1929-30; 1932 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 6)
      - Toor, Frances (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 6)
        -See also Ser.VIII, Mexico - Notes, 1929-30; 1932
    - Mexico - Notes, [1929?-30] (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 6)
      La Conquista, mexican dances; some in Spanish
    - Mexico, 1930; 2 Notebooks (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 6)
    - [Mexico] - Notes taken by Benjamin Villarán, Jr., 1930 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 6)
      - Villarán, Benjamin, Jr. (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 6)
    - Mexico - Notes, 1930-32 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 6)
      La Conquista, Santa Ana del Valle; some in Spanish & French
      - Espinosa, Aurelio M. (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 6)
      - (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 6)
    - Mexico - Notes, 1931; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 6)
      "La Conquista acquired at Mitla"
    - [Mexico] - Notes from Burgoa sent by Ralph L. Beals, 1933 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 6)
      - Beals, Ralph (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 6)
    - Mexico - Notes, n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 6)
    - [Mexico] - Notes, n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 6)
      -See also Ser.VIII, [Mexico] - Notes, n.d. [tales]
    - [Michoacan] - Notebook, 1931 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 6)
      excerpt
      -For additional materials, see Ser.IV, [Mexico] - Notes, n.d.
    - Miscellaneous - Notes, n.d.; 4 Folders (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 6)
    - Nambé - Notebook, 1926 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 6)
    - Navaho - Notebook, 1915-16 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 6)
    - [Negro Folklore] - Notes, 1899; 1916-1918; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 7)
      -See also Ser.IV, [American Folklore] - Notes, 1895-1903; 1919; n.d.
    - Nova Scotia, 1923 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 7)
      numbered 1-8, 9a, 9b
      - Barbeau, C.M. (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 7)
      - Columbia University. Library (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 7)
      - Fauset, Arthur Huff (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 7)
      - Hayshaw, Beatrice M. (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 7)
      - Robinson, Evangeline M., 10 Notebooks (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 7)
    - Nova Scotia - Notes, 1923 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 7)
      - Morris, Stephen (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 7)
    - Pima - Notebook, 1926 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 7)
    - Pueblo Indian Culture, Distribution in (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 8)
      chart
    - Pueblo Indian Dances, 1925 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 8)
      Santa Fe Fiesta program
    - [Pueblo Indians, Ceremonial Organization and Ceremonies] (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 8)
      charts
    - Pueblo Indians, Distribution of Rites (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 8)
    - San Felipe - Notebook, 1920 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 8)
      contains Isleta and Sandia material
    - San Ildefonso, [1923?]; 2 Notebooks (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 8)
    - San Juan, 1923; 4 Notebooks (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 8)
    - Sandia, 1920 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 8)
    - Santa Clara, [1923?]; 2 Notebooks (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 8)
    - San[to] Domingo - Notebook, 1920 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 8)
      -See Ser.IV, Isleta - Notebook #2, 1920
    - Sia (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 8)
      -See Ser.IV, Zuni - Notes by Alfred L. Kroeber, Folders #1-5, [ca.1919?]
    - Portia Smiley, n.d.; 2 Notebooks (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 8)
    - Spain - Notebook, 1928 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 8)
      -See also Ser.VIII, Spain, 1928
    - Spanish Riddles & Tales - Notebook, 1922 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 8)
    - [Stenographer's Notebooks] (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 9)
      all in Gregg shorthand
      - Notebook #1, Nov.-Dec. 1929 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 9)
      - Notebook #2, [1929] (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 9)
      - Notebook #3, Apr.-Jun. 1930 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 9)
      - Notebook #4, Jun.-Sep. 1930 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 9)
      - Notebook #5, Sep.-Nov. 1930 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 9)
      - Notebook #6, 1930-31 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 9)
      - Notebook #7, 1931 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 9)
      - Notebook #8, 1932 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 9)
      - Notebook #9, 1932-33 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 9)
      - Notebook #10, Apr.-Oct. 1933 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 9)
      - Notebook #11, Mar.-May 1934 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 9)
      - Notebook #12, Oct.-Nov. 1934 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 9)
      - Notebook #13, 1934 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 9)
      - Notebook #14, 1935? (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 9)
      - Notebook #15, n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 9)
      - Notebook #16, n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 9)
    - [Sudanese Tales] - Notes collected by Edward Atiyah, 1926 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 9)
      - Atiyah, Edward (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 9)
        -For additional materials, see also: Ser.IV, Egypt/Khartoum - Notebooks #1-11, 1926; Khartoum - Notebook by George Bourtos, 1926; [Egyptian, Sudanese and Arabian Tales] - Notes, 1926
    - Taos - Notes, ca.1930 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 10)
      - [Luhan], Mabel [Dodge] (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 10)
        -See also Ser.I, Johnson, Melville
        - Mss. - "Taos the Brilliant"
    - Tesuque - Notebook, 1923 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 10)
    - Tesuque - Notebook, 1925 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 10)
    - Tesuque - Notes, n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 10)
    - Tewa (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 10)
      -For additional materials, see Ser.IV, [Indian Languages] - Notebook; Zuni - Notes by Alfred L. Kroeber, Folders #1-5, [ca.1919?]
    - [Tewa] - Notebook, 1920-21 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 10)
      journal, not taken by ECP
    - Tewa - Notebook, 1923 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 10)
    - Tewa - Notebook, 1924 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 10)
      -See Ser.IV, Hopi-Tewa - Notebook, 1924
    - Tiwa (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 10)
    - Zuni - Notebooks - [Journal], 1915; 2 Notebooks (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 10)
    - Zuni - Notebook - [Topics], 1915; 4 Notebooks (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 10)
    - [Zuni] - Notebook, [1915?] (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 10)
    - Zuni - Notebook, 1915-16 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 11)
      includes material on Acoma and Navaho
      - Kroeber, A[lfred] L. (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 11)
      - Lowie, Robert H. (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 11)
    - Zuni - Notebook - [Journal], 1915-16 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 11)
    - Zuni - Notebook, 1915-17 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 11)
      - Lewis, Margaret L. (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 11)
    - [Zuni], 1917; 8 Notebooks (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 11)
    - [Zuni] - Notebook, [1917?] (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 11)
    - Zuni, Feb. 1918 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 11)
      - Notebooks #1-5 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 11)
      - Notebooks #6-7, Feb. 1918 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 12)
    - Zuni - Notes, [Feb. 1918?] (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 12)
      -See also Ser.VIII, Zuni - Notes, [Feb. 1918?]
    - Zuni - Notes, 1918 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 12)
      - American Museum of Natural (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 12)
      - History (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 12)
      - Goddard, P.E., 2 Folders (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 12)
    - Zuni - Notes, 1919 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 12)
      calendar
    - Zuni - Notes by Alfred L. Kroeber, [ca.1919?]; 5 Folders (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 12)
      contains material on Hano, Hopi, Jemez, Laguna, Sia, Tewa, and Tiwa
    - Zuni, 1920; 3 Notebooks (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 12)
    - Zuni - Notebook, 1921 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 12)
    - Zuni - Notebook, 1923 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 13)
    - [Zuni] - Notes, 1923; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 13)
    - [Zuni] - Notebook by Owen Cattell, [1924] (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 13)
    - Zuni - Notebook, 1932 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 13)
    - Zuni - Notes, 1932 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 13)
      - Lewis, Margaret (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 13)
    - Zuni and Laguna Songs - Notes (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 13)
      re: recordings made from 1915 to early 1920
    - Zuni, Isleta at - Notebook, 1926 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 13)
    - Zuni Ceremonial Pottery - Notes, [1932] (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 13)
      Laboratory of Santa Fe, N.M. designs
    - [Zuni Pottery Designs], 1918? (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 13)
    - Zuni [Vocabulary] - Notebook recorded by Frank Hamilton Cushing, 1880-81 (Box Papers-II Series-IV: 13)
  - Series V. Herbert Parsons Papers, 1894-1931
    primarily contains papers of Elsie Clews Parsons' husband. This series is narrow in its focus; it contains personal correspondence with their children and other relatives, and includes material on his work with the American Expeditionary Forces in Europe in 1918. The bulk of the material in this series dates from 1916 to 1920. Herbert's correspondence with Elsie appears in Series II. N.B. The bulk of Herbert Parsons' papers are deposited in the Columbia University Libraries.
    - American Expeditionary Forces, 1918; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-V: 1)
    - American Expeditionary Forces - Bills and Receipts, 1918 (Box Papers-II Series-V: 1)
    - American Express Co., 1918 (Box Papers-II Series-V: 1)
    - Berndt, Charles, 1918 (Box Papers-II Series-V: 1)
    - Brinley, Godfry M., 1916 (Box Papers-II Series-V: 1)
    - Burrill, William L., 1918 (Box Papers-II Series-V: 1)
    - Calder, William M., [1919] (Box Papers-II Series-V: 1)
    - Clews, Lucy, n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-V: 1)
      mother-in-law of HP
    - Day, Clarence, [1920] (Box Papers-II Series-V: 1)
    - Flanagan, Mary A., 1894 (Box Papers-II Series-V: 1)
    - Fontaine, Marie Louise, 1918; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-V: 1)
    - Hackett, Francis, n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-V: 1)
    - Hamilton, Angus, 1913 (Box Papers-II Series-V: 1)
    - Handy, Ethalinda T., 1918 (Box Papers-II Series-V: 1)
    - Haslam, Lewis S., 1918 (Box Papers-II Series-V: 1)
    - Hecht, William C., 1918 (Box Papers-II Series-V: 1)
    - Hecht, William C., Jr., 1918 (Box Papers-II Series-V: 1)
    - James, Lucy, 1916-18 (Box Papers-II Series-V: 1)
    - Lee, Ivy L., 1918 (Box Papers-II Series-V: 1)
    - Lenox Library Association, 1918 (Box Papers-II Series-V: 1)
    - McCain, [?], 1918 (Box Papers-II Series-V: 1)
    - Merrill, William Pierson, 1918 (Box Papers-II Series-V: 1)
    - Mills, Ogden L., 1918 (Box Papers-II Series-V: 1)
    - Morgan, D.P., 1917; 1919 (Box Papers-II Series-V: 1)
      nephew of HP
    - Morgan, D. Percy, 1895-98 (Box Papers-II Series-V: 1)
    - Morgan, Edith Parsons, 1903-15; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-V: 1)
      sister of HP
    - Morgan, Helen, 1914 (Box Papers-II Series-V: 1)
      niece of HP
    - Morgan, J.P., 1914; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-V: 1)
    - Nolan, Dennis E., 1918 (Box Papers-II Series-V: 1)
    - Olcott, J. Van Vechten, 1919 (Box Papers-II Series-V: 1)
    - Olympic (Ship). Marine Dept., 1914 (Box Papers-II Series-V: 1)
    - Parsons, Constance, 1902-20; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-V: 1)
    - Parsons, Edward L., 1912-16; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-V: 1)
    - Parsons, Elsie (Lissa) (Box Papers-II Series-V: 1)
      - Folder #1, 1909-17 (Box Papers-II Series-V: 1)
      - Folder #2, 1918 (Box Papers-II Series-V: 1)
      - Folder #3, 1919-21; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-V: 1)
    - Parsons, Florence Van Cortlandt Bishop (Mrs. John Edward), 1912-15; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-V: 1)
    - Parsons[?], Gertrude, 1902-18; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-V: 1)
    - Parsons, Herbert, 1910 (Box Papers-II Series-V: 1)